<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Relm4 on Eberhardt blog</title><link>https://aaronerhardt.github.io/blog/tags/relm4/</link><description>Recent content in Relm4 on Eberhardt blog</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.138.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aaronerhardt.github.io/blog/tags/relm4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A new Relm 4 you: announcing Relm4 v0.4!</title><link>https://aaronerhardt.github.io/blog/posts/announcing_relm4_v0.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaronerhardt.github.io/blog/posts/announcing_relm4_v0.4/</guid><description>&lt;p>A new realm is here for you to explore! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce Relm4 v0.4, our biggest release so far!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="about-relm4">About Relm4&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Relm4 is an idiomatic GUI library inspired by &lt;a href="https://elm-lang.org/">Elm&lt;/a> and based on &lt;a href="https://crates.io/crates/gtk4">gtk4-rs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We believe that GUI development should be easy, productive and delightful.&lt;br>
The &lt;a href="https://crates.io/crates/gtk4">gtk4-rs&lt;/a> crate already provides everything you need to write modern, beautiful and cross-platform applications.
Built on top of this foundation, Relm4 makes developing more idiomatic, simpler and faster and enables you to become productive in just a few hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Announcing Relm4 v0.2</title><link>https://aaronerhardt.github.io/blog/posts/announcing_relm4_v0.2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaronerhardt.github.io/blog/posts/announcing_relm4_v0.2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Roughly one month after the first stable release a I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce the second stable release of Relm4! 🚀🚀🚀&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-relm4">About Relm4&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We believe that GUI development should be easy, productive and delightful.&lt;br>
The &lt;a href="https://github.com/gtk-rs/gtk4-rs">gtk4-rs&lt;/a> crate already provides everything you need to write modern, beautiful and cross-platform applications. Built on top of this foundation, Relm4 makes developing more idiomatic, simpler and faster and enables you to become productive in just a few hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Announcing Relm4 v0.1</title><link>https://aaronerhardt.github.io/blog/posts/announcing_relm4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaronerhardt.github.io/blog/posts/announcing_relm4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Roughly one month after the first beta release and countless hours of work I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce the first stable release of Relm4! 🎉🎉🎉&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-relm4">About Relm4&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Relm4 is an idiomatic GUI library inspired by &lt;a href="https://elm-lang.org/">Elm&lt;/a> and based on &lt;a href="https://crates.io/crates/gtk4">gtk4-rs&lt;/a>.
It is a new version of &lt;a href="https://github.com/antoyo/relm">relm&lt;/a> that&amp;rsquo;s built from scratch and is compatible with &lt;a href="https://www.gtk.org/">GTK4&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://gitlab.gnome.org/GNOME/libadwaita">libadwaita&lt;/a>. The main goals are productivity, flexibility, simplicity and maintainability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last beta releases, the development slowly calmed down up to a point where I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable releasing the first stable version. I&amp;rsquo;ve already started porting my existing app I wrote with GTK3 and relm to use GTK4, libadwaita and Relm4 and I was very pleased with the productivity I was able to archive. I believe Relm4 offers a truly outstanding experience for GUI development in Rust.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Relm4 beta released 🎉</title><link>https://aaronerhardt.github.io/blog/posts/relm_beta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaronerhardt.github.io/blog/posts/relm_beta/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="whats-relmhttpsgithubcomantoyorelm">What&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://github.com/antoyo/relm">relm&lt;/a>?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Relm is described on its repository as an &amp;ldquo;idiomatic, GTK+-based, GUI library, inspired by Elm, written in Rust&amp;rdquo; and has more than 2000 GitHub stars and over 36.000 downloads on &lt;a href="https://crates.io/crates/relm">crates.io&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I first started with GUI development in Rust and experimented with &lt;a href="https://github.com/gtk-rs/gtk3-rs">gtk-rs&lt;/a> I had a rough time because I was completely new to GUI development and GTK. Relm on the other side provided me the examples and structure I needed to get productive in just a couple of hours. Over the next weeks I continued using relm to work on an application I write at my job and was very pleased with the productivity I was able to archive.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>